(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
戌神ころね
Inugami Korone
角巻わため
Tsunomaki Watame
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
君が飛び降りるのならば
作詞：Sakurai 作曲：Omoi
If you're going to jump
Lyrics: Sakurai Composition: Omoi
いきなり歌い始めてごめんね
Sorry for suddenly starting to sing
ちょっとだけそのまま聞いててね
Just listen to it as it is for a bit
本日お伝えしたいのは
What I want to tell you today is
とても大事な君のこと
About you, who are very important
たまには喧嘩もしてきたけど
We've had fights sometimes, but
だからこそ何でも知ってんだ
That's why I know everything
君の長所は真面目なこと
Your strong point is your seriousness
ただ妄想癖がひどい！
But your delusions are terrible!
君が飛び降りるのならば僕は
If you're going to jump, I'll
笑って一緒に飛び降りる
smile and jump with you
止めてくれるとでも思ったか！
Did you think I'd stop you!
僕らの絆を見くびるな！
Don't underestimate our bond!
そして手を繋いで落ちていこう
And let's fall while holding hands
地面目掛けてピースしよう
Let's make a peace sign towards the ground
でもそういえば何かを
But come to think of it, something
忘れているような……
feels like I'm forgetting something...
ああそうだ！
Oh, right!
見たいテレビがあった！
There was a TV show I wanted to watch!
やっぱり飛ぶの後でにしませんか！
How about we put off the jumping until later after all!
君に出会ってからというもの
Ever since I met you...
全てとにかくおかしくなった
Everything has just gone weird
占いなんか信じてなかったのに
I didn't believe in fortune-telling, but
気付けばのめり込んでいた
before I knew it, I was into it
変な音楽ばかり勧めて
Always recommending weird music
変な漫画ばかり押し付けて
Always pushing weird manga on me
ヒトの人生左右しといて
Influencing someone's life like that
ふざけんな覚えてろこの野郎
Stop messing around, I'll remember this, you jerk!
君が飛び降りるのならば僕は
If you're going to jump...
君よりも先に飛び降りる
...I'll jump before you do
説得されるとでも思ったか
Did you think I'd be talked out of it?
僕の馬鹿さを甘く見るな
Don't underestimate my stupidity
え、何 あのマンガの主人公が
Eh, what? That manga protagonist
今週敵を倒したって？
defeated an enemy this week?
って何回言えば分かるんだ
How many times do I have to say it for you to understand?
僕は単行本派なんだ！
I'm a volume reader!
ああ 次が出るのいつだっけ
Ah, when is the next volume coming out again?
それ読むまでは絶対許さない！
Until I read that, I'll never forgive you!
いつか僕らは
Someday, we...
答え合わせすら出来なくなるかな
...might not even be able to compare notes anymore
そんな未来は
A future like that...
忘れるまで決めたまんま
...I've decided to keep it that way until I forget
さあさあレディース・エン・ジェントルメン
Come now, ladies and gentlemen
これよりお目にかけますは
What I'm about to show you is...
一世一代の大舞台
...the stage of a lifetime
泣いても笑ってもどうぞごゆっくり
Whether you cry or laugh, please enjoy yourselves
君が飛び降りるのならば僕は
If you're going to jump...
笑って一緒に飛び降りる
...I'll jump together with you, laughing
止めてくれるとでも思ったか
Did you think I'd stop you?
僕らの絆を見くびるな！
Don't underestimate our bond!
僕らが出会う世界でも
Even in the world where we meet
またこんな風になれたらいいね
I hope we can be like this again
生まれ変わったら何になるか
Let's see what we'll be when we're reborn
本で占ってみようか？
with a fortune-telling book
君は「玉ねぎ」 僕は「タイヤ」
You're an "onion", and I'm a "tire"
やっぱり飛ぶの今度にしませんか...？
Actually, why don't we save the jumping for next time...?
ホントのホントに飛べる日目指して
Truly, aiming for the day we can really fly
もうちょっとだけ一緒に居ませんか！
Won't you stay with me just a little longer!
UNDEAD
作詞・作曲: Ayase
Lyrics & Music: Ayase
UNHAPPY?
ねえ悩み人の子よ
Hey there, troubled soul
人ならざる者も
And you, non-human beings too
BE HAPPY!
絶えず目指せよ
Always keep aiming for it
生きているんだし
Since you're alive
目を逸らした過去も退屈な未来も
The past you turned away from and the boring future
カウンセリング やれやれ古今東西
Counseling, oh boy, from all times and places
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY?
UNDEAD!
ねえねえねえ なんだかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, why do I feel like...
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
...I'm fighting somehow?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Can't touch, don't want to touch
過去の自分自分自分自分と
My past self, self, self, self
もうとっくに死んでる
Already been dead for ages
透明な亡霊と対決
Facing off with a transparent ghost
痛い毛羽立った記憶の奥
Deep within those painful, frayed memories
残念！もういないのに
Too bad! Even though they're already gone
あれ これがいいアイロニーね
Oh, what a nice irony
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Am I the one being seen through now?
ナンセンス！消えないレッテル
Nonsense! A label that won't fade
YES！要はコンプレックス
Yes! Basically, it's a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like being possessed
吐き出したまま まだ放せない
Left just as I spat it out, still can't let go
在りし日の自分
My past self
UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead, that chain of you and you
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
Living means continuing to change
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content with wallowing in unhappiness
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to try to be happy
この世 この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
What will come out next? A demon or a serpent?
あてあてやっと始まる物語
Aim, aim, the story is finally beginning
さあ、人か化け物か古今東西
Now, human or monster? From all times and places
諸行無常
Impermanence of all things
Past & Future / Can't change the Past
Past & Future / Run for the Future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ
何の希望もない期待出来ない
Somehow, why is it that I can't
hope or expect anything from the future?
ような気がして
I feel that way
もう随分生きている
I've lived quite a long time
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Sick of déjà vu and templates
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of anything wonderful happening
残念！詰んだ経験の因果
Too bad! The causality of exhausted experiences
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
A hollowed-out myth and a boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Basically, I want stimulation
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
Got tired of it, got used to it
なんて整っていくガイダンス
Such neat guidance
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
塞がれていくみたい 吸い尽くして
It's like being blocked, sucking it all up
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That, this, all of them taste the same
UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead, that chain of you and you
何時の世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
In any age, the past and future are in the now
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Stubbornly fulfill the act of living
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending
UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
You're not dead, I'm talking to you
幸せを諦めてしまうな人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness, remain human
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just getting used to suffering and enduring it...
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
you might as well be dead, a walking corpse, undead
UNLUCKY?
ねえ悩み人の子よ
Hey there, troubled soul
人ならざる者も
And you, non-human beings too
BE HAPPY!
絶えず目指せよ
Always keep aiming for it
生きているんだろう
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも幸せに出るのも
Whether you wallow in unhappiness or find happiness
全部全部全部お前だ
It's all, all, all you
古今東西一切合切森羅万象
From all times and places, every single thing, all creation
人の在る所に 何時も憂い事
Wherever people are, there is always sorrow.
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters.
はい！というわけで、皆さん、しゅばーす！
Alright! So everyone, Shuba-su!
ホロライブ2期生、アイドル大空スバル...
Hololive 2nd Gen idol, Oozora Subaru...
大空スバル6周年記念ライブ『星灯』にお越しくださり、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Oozora Subaru's 6th anniversary live, 'Hoshiakari'!
ライブ始まる！始まるよー！
The live is starting! It's starting!
ということで、今回の配信のハッシュタグは右上、こちらになるので、
So, the hashtag for this stream is this one in the top right,
Xでいっぱいポストしてください！よろしくお願いします！
so please post a lot on X! Thank you!
ハッシュタグは #大空スバル6周年ライブ になります！
The hashtag is #OozoraSubaru6thAnniversaryLive!
はい！ということでね、なんか、駆け抜けてきましたけれども、
Yes! So, we've been running through it,
ここからまだまだライブは続きますので、よろしくお願いします！
but the live will continue from here, so please stay with me!
ということで、次の曲はなんと、スバルの大好きなあのゲーム、あの曲を歌いたいと思います！
So, for the next song, I'm going to sing that song from that game I love so much!
それでは聴いてください。ちょっとじゃあ場所に移動して... よいしょ、よいしょ。
Please listen to it. I'll just move to the spot... There we go.
はい、ということで。それでは聴いてください。
Yes, so. Please listen to it.
『恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと』
'Itoshisa to Setsunasa to Kokoroyousa to'
恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと
Itoshisa to Setsunasa to Kokoroyousa to
Longing, and sadness, and reassurance
いつも感じている あなたへと向かって
I always feel them, directed towards you
あやまちはおそれずに 進むあなたを
You who move forward without fearing mistakes
涙は見せないで 見つめていたいよ
Without showing tears, I want to keep watching you
遠い空を あの日眺めていた
I was gazing at the distant sky that day
やりかけの青春も 経験も そのままで
Leaving my unfinished youth and experiences as they were
永遠を 夢見ていた あの日は今
Those days when I dreamed of eternity are now
もう二度と 繰り返さずに 戻らずに 生きること
Living without ever repeating or returning
できなくて あこがれて
Unable to do so, longing
でも少しずつ わかってきた
But bit by bit, I've come to understand
戦うこと 悲しくて 泣きたくて 叫びたくても
Even if fighting is sad, and I want to cry and scream
あなたを信じてる 言葉にできない
I believe in you, words can't describe it
あやまちはおそれずに 進むあなたを
You who move forward without fearing mistakes
涙は見せないで 信じていたいよ
Without showing tears, I want to believe in you
誰の目にも 止まることないまま
Without catching anyone's eye
街角のポスターは 色あせて 消えてゆく
The poster on the street corner fades and disappears
だけど あなたへの想いはきっと
But surely, my feelings for you
消えないで いつまでも 迷わずに 残ってる
Won't disappear, remaining forever without hesitation
いつでも 会えなくて
Even if we can't always meet
でも世界中で 一人だけは 伝えたい
But in all the world, there's just one person I want to tell
恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと
Longing, and sadness, and reassurance
いつも感じている あなたへと向かって
I always feel them, directed towards you
あやまちはおそれずに 進むあなたを
You who move forward without fearing mistakes
涙は見せないで 見つめていたいよ
Without showing tears, I want to keep watching you
恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと
With tenderness, sadness, and courage
ホットダック！
作詞・作曲・編曲：なみぐる
Hot Duck!
Lyrics/Music/Arrangement: Namiguru
クワッ クワッ クワッ クワッ
Quack quack quack quack
食わず嫌いは non-non-non
Picky eating is non-non-non
クワッ クワッ クワッ クワッ
Quack quack quack quack
我らは神代のソーセージ
We are the ancient sausages
行くよー！
Here we go!
ホットダック・ダック・ダック
Hot Duck-Duck-Duck
グッドラック・ラック・ラック
Good Luck-Luck-Luck
ずっとワクワク みんなヤワヤワしっくしっく
Always excited, everyone soft and squishy
ホットダック・ダック・ダック
Hot Duck-Duck-Duck
グッドラック・ラック・ラック
Good Luck-Luck-Luck
ずっとラッキー これが昼の歌劇
Always lucky, this is the noon opera
始まりました 今日のフェスティバル
Today's festival has begun
ズバッと飛び出て ジャンジャンジャン
Jump out with a bang, bang bang bang
バズり散らした スバルとダック
Subaru and the duck went viral
主役は食わないでえええ
Don't eat the main character!
武士は食わねど高楊枝
A samurai pretends to be full even when hungry
でもアヒル食わねば腹が減る
But if you don't eat duck, you'll be hungry
(ほら減った)
(See, I'm hungry)
料理の基本 さしすせそ
The basics of cooking: Sa-Shi-Su-Se-So
はい！
Yes!
砂糖 塩 酢 せうゆ 味噌
Sugar, salt, vinegar, soy sauce, miso
さーさーさー ソーセージ
Sa-sa-sa- sausage!
ホットダダダダ 熱いビート
Hot-da-da-da-da hot beat
ズバッとズバッと 鳴らしてけ
Make it ring out with a bang
ホットダダダダ 丸い地球を
Hot-da-da-da-da, the round Earth
くるっとくるっと 回してけ
Spin it around and around
水掻き 汗掻き べそ掻き だけど
Webbed feet, sweating, crying, but
スバルの努力でいっぱい風受ける手
With Subaru's effort, catch plenty of wind
(トゥ！)
(Tou!)
ホットダック・ダック・ダック
Hot Duck-Duck-Duck
グッドラック・ラック・ラック
Good Luck-Luck-Luck
ずっとワクワク みんなヤワヤワしっくしっく
Always excited, everyone soft and squishy
ホットダック・ダック・ダック
Hot Duck-Duck-Duck
グッドラック・ラック・ラック
Good Luck-Luck-Luck
ずっとラッキー これが昼の歌劇
Always lucky, this is the noon opera
パンチラインが 今日も炸裂だ
The punchline exploded today too
ドカッと爆受け どわっはっは
Huge laugh, dowa-ha-ha
ふと思い出した 失敗談も
The failures I suddenly remembered
笑いに変えちゃいましょう
Let's turn them into laughter
(おっおっおっ)
(Oh-oh-oh)
浅い川も深く渡れ
Cross even shallow rivers as if they were deep
でも深く渡れば骨濡れる
But if you cross deep, you'll get soaked to the bone
(びちゃびちゃ)
(Splashing)
喋りの基本 さしすせそ
The basics of talking: Sa-Shi-Su-Se-So
(はい！) さすがです 知らなかった すごいセンスある
(Yes!) As expected! I didn't know that! You have great sense!
さーさーさー ソーセージ
Sa-sa-sa- sausage!
ホットダダダダ 熱いハート
Hot-da-da-da-da hot heart
もっともっと 燃やしてけ
Keep burning more and more
ホットダダダダ 熱いトークを
Hot-da-da-da-da hot talk
くるっとくるっと 回してけ
Spin it around and around
抜き足 差し足 アヒル足
Sneaking, cautiously, duck feet
だけどペタペタ鳴るから居場所がバレちゃうぜ
But the splashing sound will give away your location
スバとも あひじょ その他大勢
Subatomo, Ahijo, and everyone else
スバルの魅力でいっぱい風受ける手
With Subaru's charm, catch plenty of wind
(トゥ！)
(Tou!)
クワッ クワッ クワッ クワッ
Quack quack quack quack
食わず嫌いは non-non-non
Picky eating is non-non-non
クワッ クワッ クワッ クワッ
Quack quack quack quack
我らは神代のソーセージ
We are the ancient sausages
睡蓮花
作詞・作曲：湘南乃風
Suirenka
Lyrics/Music: Shounan no Kaze
睡蓮の花のように
Like a water lily flower
朝日に向き今日もうたう
Facing the morning sun, I sing again today
睡蓮の花のように
Like a water lily flower
この思い水面に光る
These feelings shine on the water surface
花びらが流した涙
The tears shed by the petals
貴方は笑っていますか？
Are you smiling?
上がりまくる季節がきた
The season for getting hyped has come
ヤバくなれるのは誰
Who can get the craziest?
俺！ 俺！ 俺・俺・俺・俺！
Me! Me! Me, me, me, me!
Ah 真夏のジャンボリー
Ah, midsummer jamboree
レゲエ＜砂浜＜＜Big Wave
Reggae < Sandy beach << Big Wave
Ah 悪ノリのハートに
Ah, to the mischievous heart
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome Weekend
Totally hardcore Welcome Weekend
Ah 灼熱のジャンボリー
Ah, scorching jamboree
暴れまくっていいぜ!!
It's okay to go wild!!
Ah 冷めないで Summer Dream
Ah, don't cool down Summer Dream
濡れたまんまでいっちゃって
Just go while still wet
夏だぜ (Yeah!!)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!)
夏風 (Furu!!)
Summer breeze (Furu!!)
夏晴れ (Yeah!!)
Sunny summer (Yeah!!)
夏バテ (Boo!!)
Summer fatigue (Boo!!)
またコイツで決まりだ 騒げ Summer Again
Decided by this one again, make some noise Summer Again
青く晴れた日を笑う太陽
The sun laughing at the blue sunny day
溢れる希望 結ぶ靴紐に期待のせて
Loading hope onto tied shoelaces
風を連れて 夢の種抱えるため
Taking the wind, to embrace the seeds of dreams
今走り出そう
Let's start running now
黄色いバス越え
Beyond the yellow bus
黄色いバス越え 江ノ島方面
Past the yellow bus, heading towards Enoshima
スゲェ混み合ってる
It's super crowded
ひまわり色した空への冒険
Adventure to the sunflower-colored sky
手取りあって
Hand in hand
確かな思い出残さなけりゃ それ新たな明日は輝かないから
If we don't leave certain memories, a new tomorrow won't shine
さあ 笑顔に会いにいこう！！
Now, let's go meet the smiles!!
やって来たぜ イイ風 イイ風 青い空
Here it comes, a good breeze, a good breeze, blue sky
何やってもいいんじゃね！？そんな気分で
Anything goes, right!? With that kind of mood
Yeah!!
フランクフルトを頬張りながら
While stuffing our faces with frankfurters
バナナボートでゴール目指す
Aiming for the goal on a banana boat
シーズンに火つく
The season's catching fire
コケてるハイヒールの姉ちゃんを横目に
Glancing at the older girl tripping in high heels
記念に「ハイチーズ！！」
Say cheese!! for a memory
Ah
真夏の Jamboree
Midsummer Jamboree
レゲエ 砂浜 Big wave
Reggae, sandy beach, Big wave
Ah
悪ノリの Heartbeat
Mischievous Heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome weekend
Super intense Welcome weekend
Ah
灼熱の Jamboree
Scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ！！
It's okay to go wild!!
Ah
冷めないで Summer dream
Don't cool down, Summer dream
濡れたまんまでイっちゃって！！
Go for it while you're still wet!!
夏だぜ
It's summer
Yeah!!
夏だぜ
It's summer
Yeah!!
夏晴れ
Summer clear sky
Yeah!!
夏風
Summer breeze
Fwu!!
夏バテ
Summer fatigue
Fwu!!
またコイツで決まりだ Summer again
It's decided by this guy again, Summer again
突然降り出した雨
Rain that suddenly started falling
ベッドで涙浮かべ
Floating tears in bed
小せえ声で「なんで俺だけ…」
In a small voice, "Why only me..."
いや 潜んで待つだけ…
No, just lurking and waiting...
待ち受けにしている写メ
The photo on the wallpaper
変顔で思わず吹き出して
Bursting out laughing at the funny face
泣き言なんて言えるか
How can I say complaints
バカヤローが 寂しくなんかねぇ！！
You idiot, I'm not lonely at all!!
さあ自分との戦い勝てば
Now, if I win the battle with myself
大切な人に会えるはずさ
I should be able to meet the person precious to me
頑張っていればお天道様が
If I do my best, the sun god
必ず微笑んでくれるさ
Will surely smile upon me
もう一度 君に包まれたくて
Wanting to be enveloped by you once more
走り抜けて来たよ
I've come running through
幾つもの季節を
Many seasons
やっと出会えた
I've finally met you
Ah
真夏の Jamboree
Midsummer Jamboree
レゲエ 砂浜 Big wave
Reggae, sandy beach, Big wave
Ah
悪ノリの Heartbeat
Mischievous Heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome weekend
Super intense Welcome weekend
Ah
灼熱の Jamboree
Scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ！！
It's okay to go wild!!
Ah
冷めないで Summer dream
Don't cool down, Summer dream
濡れたまんまでイっちゃって！！
Go for it while you're still wet!!
夏の日差しが眩しすぎて
The summer sun is too dazzling
本当の笑顔見えなくなって
I can't see the true smile anymore
空を見上げることも忘れ
Forgetting to look up at the sky
地面向いて足踏みしてるんじゃねぇ！！
Don't just face the ground and stomp!!
約束された明日なんてねぇ！！
There is no promised tomorrow!!
当たり前なんて思ってるんじゃねぇ！！
Don't think of it as natural!!
朝が迎えに来る幸せ
The happiness of the morning coming to greet you
睡蓮とともに…
Together with the water lily...
花びらが流した愛が
The love that the petals shed
貴方に届いていますか？
Is it reaching you?
若き小僧のこの涙
This tear of a young boy
笑い声になるまで
Until it becomes laughter
Ah
人生という旅に出た俺たちには
For us who have set out on a journey called life
後戻りはない
There is no turning back
いつの日にかあの睡蓮の花のように
One day, like that water lily flower
今まで流した涙の泉の上咲かせ
Let it bloom on the fountain of tears shed until now
濡れたまんまでイっちゃって！！
Go for it while you're still wet!!
また始まった また走り出した Season
It started again, Season started running again
夏は好きか！？ (Yeah!!)
Do you like summer!? (Yeah!!)
間違いない また始まった砂浜のリズム
No doubt, the rhythm of the sandy beach started again
付き合いな！！ (Yeah!!)
Go along with it!! (Yeah!!)
目が合って 気が合って 間違いない Season
Eyes met, spirits matched, no doubt Season
欲望のまんま！！ (Yeah!!)
Just as desired!! (Yeah!!)
出会って 泣いて 笑って 泣いて 笑って 泣いて 笑って 泣いて
Met, cried, laughed, cried, laughed, cried, laughed, cried
濡れたまんまでイっちゃって！！
Go for it while you're still wet!!
はい！ということで、ミコズとミオしゃとスバルで「睡蓮花」お送りしましたー！
Alright! So, Miko-chi, Mio-sha, and Subaru performed "Suirenka" for you!
どうだったでしょうかー！
How did you like it?!
睡蓮花はですね、なんとちょっとスバルが、
Regarding "Suirenka", Subaru...
あの沖縄でね、この3人で聞いた湘南の風がもう忘れられなさすぎて、もう絶対歌いたいってなって、ちょっとね、歌いました。
The Shounan no Kaze song the three of us heard in Okinawa was so unforgettable that I just had to sing it, so we did.
ミオしゃ、みこち、参加してくれてありがとう！
Mio-sha, Mikochi, thanks for joining in!
はい、ということで、ちょっとここまでのですね、振り返りをしてきたいなと思うんですけど、
Right, so, I'd like to look back on the performance so far.
まずですね、「恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと」ではですね、
First, for "Itoshisa to Setsunasa to Kokorotsuyosa to"...
スバルもう絶対に今年はストリートファイターの曲歌いたいと思ってたのでですね、
I really wanted to sing a Street Fighter song this year,
このねメンバーでね、みんなでね、歌えてすごい嬉しかったです。
so I was really happy to sing it with everyone in that group.
そしてですね、次に「ホットドッグ」なんですけど、
And then, "Hot Dog"...
まあスバルのオリ曲をですね、おかゆとあためっていうこのちょっとスギャクメンバーで、
we sang my original song with Okayu and Atame, that mischievous group,
ちょっとね、歌って、可愛く歌ってくれてすごいね、楽しかったです。
they sang it so cutely, it was really fun.
みんな参加してくれてありがとう！
Thanks to everyone who joined!
そして見てくれたみんなもありがとうございます！
And thanks to everyone watching!
はい、ということで、ここでちょっとライブステージの紹介をしたいと思います！
Right, now I'd like to introduce the live stage!
なんとですね、今年のこの素敵なステージはですね、色んなこだわりポイントが詰まってるんですけど、
This year's wonderful stage has a lot of special features, but...
まずですね、えー、この後ろのくそデカモニター！
first off, this humongous monitor in the back!
これがですね、結構お気に入りです。
I really like this one.
このなんかあのサイズ感がめちゃいいです。
The scale of it is just great.
そして、そのくそデカモニターの後ろにある、もうめちゃめちゃ綺麗な空！
And behind that humongous monitor is this incredibly beautiful sky!
このですね、あの背景もですね、お空の方もですね、今後何かがおこるかもしれないので、
As for the background and the sky, something might happen there later,
ぜひみんなそこにも注目してくれよな！ということで、よろしくお願いします。
so please keep an eye on it! Thank you.
そしてですね、えー、なんと今水着ということで、
And, well, since I'm in a swimsuit right now,
ぜひ皆さんたくさんスクリーンショット撮ってください。
please take lots of screenshots.
可愛いでしょ！
Cute, right?
これをですね、たくさんスクリーンショット、そして、えー、ポスト！
Take lots of screenshots and, uh, post them!
ポストしてください。ポスト！
Please post them. Post!
ハッシュタグは #大空スバル6周年ライブ、よろしくお願いします。
The hashtag is #OozoraSubaru6thAnniversaryLive. Thank you.
これ後ろとかもね、すごい可愛いんでね、
It's also really cute from the back,
ぜひ、あんまり見る機会ないと思うので。
and I don't think you get many chances to see that.
はい、ポストした？
Okay, did you post?
ポストした人！次に曲に行きたいと思いますので、ちょっとスバルは着替えてくるぞ！
Anyone who posted? I want to move on to the next song, so Subaru's going to go change!
着替えてくるぞ！わー！
I'm going to go change! Waa!
わー！ということで、皆さんこっからですね、まだまだライブは続きまーす！
Waa! Alright, everyone, the live performance continues from here!
こっからはちょっとアイドルスバをね、どんどん見せていきたいと思いますので、まだまだ盛り上がっていくぞ！
I'm going to show you more of "Idol Suba" from now on, so let's keep the energy up!
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
はい、それでは次の曲、聴いてください。
Okay, then, please listen to the next song.
いいですか？
Are you ready?
よし、それでは次の曲聴いてください、「CLEAR」。
Alright, please listen to the next song, "CLEAR".
風って 鳥って
The wind, the birds
私より自由かな
Are they freer than me?
翼がないなら 走ってくわ
If I don't have wings, I'll run
行きたいところまで
To wherever I want to go
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going Going Going Going on!
想像とは いつも違ってる
It's always different from what I imagined
何もかも完璧とはいかないけど
Not everything can be perfect, but
心のどこかに 泉があるの
There's a spring somewhere in my heart
どんなに落ち込んでも また
No matter how down I feel
透明なもので満たされていく
It gets filled with something transparent
これって これって なんていう気持ちなの
What is this feeling?
熱くて 痛くて くすぐったくて
Hot, painful, and ticklish
涙が出そう
I feel like I'm going to cry
風って 鳥って 私より自由かな
The wind, the birds, are they freer than me?
翼がないなら 走ってくわ
If I don't have wings, I'll run
行きたいところまで できるよね
To wherever I want to go, I can do it
Going Going Going Going on!
他の子にあって 私にないもの
Things other girls have that I don't
分かってはいるけど
I know that, but...
つい比べちゃうよ
I end up comparing myself.
答え合わせは
Checking the answers...
もうしたくない
...is something I don't want to do anymore.
みんなと同じじゃなくても
Even if I'm not the same as everyone else,
私にできること見つけたいの
I want to find what I can do.
夢って
Dreams...
愛って
...and love...
本当はよく知らない
...I don't really know them.
どんな色
What color are they?
どんな形
What shape do they take?
どこからやってくるの
Where do they come from?
知って
Knowing,
願って
Wishing,
それだけじゃ叶わない
That alone won't make them come true.
自信がなくても始めるんだ
I'll start even if I lack confidence.
いつかじゃなくて今
Not 'someday,' but right now.
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going Going Going Going On
泉がここにあるの
The fountain is right here.
私を司る源が
The source that governs me.
何があっても枯れたりしない
It will never dry up, no matter what happens.
諦めたつもりでもまた
Even when I think I've given up,
透明なもので満たされてゆく
I'm filled with something transparent once again.
これって これって なんていう気持ちなの
What is this feeling, what do you call it?
熱くて 痛くて くすぐったくて 涙が出そう
It's hot, it hurts, it's ticklish, I'm about to cry.
風って 鳥って 私より自由かな
I wonder if the wind and the birds are freer than I am.
翼がないなら走ってくわ 行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going Going Going Going On
Pop in 2, Pop in 2
POP IN 2
作詞：つむぎしゃち
作曲：久下真音 / つむぎしゃち
POP IN 2
Lyrics: Tsumugi Shachi
Composition: Kuge Maine / Tsumugi Shachi
Pop in 2, Pop in 2
ハ・クシテ どこへ どこへ どこへ連れてって
Hi-ding, where, where, where will you take me?
ヒ・ミツで 君は 君は 君は探せないかな
Se-cretly, I wonder if you, you, you can't find me.
現れ 私は 行き先々
Appearing, wherever I go,
後先々なら考えない
I don't think about the consequences.
パカラッパカラ まま びっくりたまいたばっか
Clip-clop, clip-clop, just being completely surprised.
手っ取り早く 虜になれ
Quickly, become captivated.
だーって 握手ただだけじゃ足りないでしょ
Cuz, just a handshake isn't enough, right?
一瞬たりとも 離れない
I won't leave you for even a second.
ガブ！
Chomp!
I love you pop you よそ見しないでね
I love you pop you, don't look away.
アイ 現れ 結局は only you
I, appearing, in the end, it's only you.
ダン 行き先々 現れ pop you now
Dan, appearing wherever you go, pop you now.
ずっとずっと隣で見て
Watch me from my side forever and ever.
ポケからPOPPIN 忍ばせ POP IN 2
POPPIN from my pocket, sneaking in, POP IN 2.
なんだりかんだり POPPIN かくれんぼ
This and that, POPPIN hide-and-seek.
ポケからPOPPIN 忍ばせ POP IN 2
POPPIN from my pocket, sneaking in, POP IN 2.
ぴょん 現れ ポップなアイコン
Boing! Appearing, a pop icon.
POPPIN HAPPY TO YOU
Pop in 2, Pop in 2
ハ・クシテ 乙女 乙女 乙女の上目して
Hi-ding, with a maiden's, maiden's, maiden's upturned look.
ヒ・ミツで 甘く 甘く 甘くかき混ぜるの
Se-cretly, stirring it sweetly, sweetly, sweetly.
群がるやつらは 行き先々
Those who crowd around, wherever they go,
ラタタ 歌えば 列外できちゃう
Ratata, if I sing, I'll step out of line.
パカラッパカラ 場所も ひっくり返るよ感
Clip-clop, clip-clop, even the place feels like it's flipping over.
手っ取り早く キュートになれ
Quickly, become cute.
キラキラ流れる星に乗って 時代を回しても
Even if I ride a sparkling shooting star and turn the ages,
1+2=2になる 式はラブ
The formula where 1+2=2 is love.
ガブ！
Chomp!
I love you pop you 置いてかないでね
I love you pop you, don't leave me behind.
アイ マシマシ 全力の only you
I, extra extra, with all my might, only you.
ダン 行き先々 絡まる pop you now
Dan, wherever you go, getting tangled, pop you now.
ずっとずっと繋いでね
Hold on to me forever and ever.
ポケからPOPPIN 狂わせて POP IN 2
POPPIN from my pocket, driving me crazy, POP IN 2.
いったりきたり POPPIN フラストレーション
Back and forth, POPPIN frustration.
ポケからPOPPIN 狂わせて POP IN 2
POPPIN from my pocket, driving me crazy, POP IN 2.
ヒュッ！
Hyu!
...かくれんぼ
...hide and seek.
ぴょん あらわれ ポッピンアイランド
Boing! I appear on Poppin' Island!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うぇーい ポッピン
Whee! Poppin'
うぇーい ポッピン ポッピン 2
Whee! Poppin', Poppin' 2
うぇーい ポッピン
Whee! Poppin'
うぇーい ポッピン ポッピン 2
Whee! Poppin', Poppin' 2
どこそこ のこのこ わかるかな？
Do you know where I'm waddling about?
客席まぎれて かなり不安
I'm quite nervous blending into the audience.
どこどこ どこどこ わかるかな？
Do you know where I am?
どこにいたって 君が一番
No matter where I am, you're the best.
ねぇ 遊んで 代わる代わる
Hey, play with me, changing back and forth.
着せ替えごっこ 上 下 横 ぷっぷっぷのぷー
Playing dress-up, up, down, side, poo-poo-poo!
天国 地獄 極楽 可愛いは 作れると申しておく
Heaven, Hell, Paradise - I'm telling you, cuteness can be made.
ねぇ いつでも 呼んで ついてきて 360度
Hey, call me anytime, follow me 360 degrees.
ドクドク むちゅちゅ中毒
Thump-thump, dizzy-dizzy addiction
I love you ポッピン 置いてかないでね
I love you Poppin', don't leave me behind.
曖昧 ましまし 全力 オンリーユー タッタッタッ...
Ambiguity extra large, all out Only You, ta-ta-ta...
I love you ポッピン 横見しないでね
I love you Poppin', don't look away.
アイアラワニ 結局 オンリーユー
Barefaced, in the end, it's Only You.
行先 咲きあらわだ ポッピンランド
Destination in full bloom, Poppin' Land.
爪先 お隣 手を繋いでね
By my side, let's hold hands.
ポッケから ポッピン 忍ばせ ポッピン 2
A Poppin' from my pocket, sneaking in Poppin' 2.
ふんだりけったり ポッピン かくれんぼ
Through thick and thin, Poppin' hide and seek.
ポッケから ポッピン 忍ばせ ポッピン 2
A Poppin' from my pocket, sneaking in Poppin' 2.
ぴょん あらわれ ポッピンアイランド
Boing! I appear on Poppin' Island!
Popping Happy to you
Happy to you Happy to you
ポッピン！ ポッピン 2！
Poppin'! Poppin' 2!
ラビットホール 作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Rabbit Hole. Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
死ぬまでピュアピュアやってんのん？
Are you gonna keep playing pure-pure until you die?
Love, blah blah blah...
ラブと超ライク パーティションはないない
Love and super like, there's no partition.
君だけが 特別じゃないんだ
You're not the only special one.
反省とか アタシに求められても
Even if you ask me for things like reflection...
ホント やんだり勘違いしないで？
...really, don't get sick of me or misunderstand.
って って って どうしてなんで期待の声ばかり忘れるの？
Wait, wait, wait, why do you only forget the voices of expectation?
最初に あれほどやめときなって伝えたじゃん
I told you to stop that so many times at first.
お純情様 あちらが出口ですが
Mr. Innocent, the exit is over there...
やっぱ 帰りたくない...ですか？
...but as I thought, you don't want to go home?
Hop step one more chance
もー やっぱビッビラビったらいいじゃん POPな愛情 踊ったらいいじゃん
Geez, as I thought, it's fine to get jittery. It's fine to dance with POP affection.
みっともないから 嫉妬しまいな 発火しちゃうよ もう くっそだせえな
It's pathetic, so stow the jealousy. It's gonna ignite, man, you're so lame.
淋しくなったら 誰でもいいじゃん 産まればいいじゃん
If you get lonely, anyone will do. Why not just be born?
嫌々愛していきたくなって 死ぬまでピュアピュアやってんのん？
Becoming reluctant to love and live, you're gonna keep playing pure-pure until you die?
やっぱビッビラビったらいいじゃん BADなダンス ハマったらいいじゃん
As I thought, it's fine to get jittery. It's fine to get hooked on a BAD dance.
やっぱり好きとか やってられんわ 馬鹿じゃないの？ もう くっそだせえな
Saying you still like me and all that, I can't take it. Are you an idiot? Man, you're so lame.
淋しくなったら 誰でもいいじゃん 産まればいいじゃん
If you get lonely, anyone will do. Why not just be born?
嫌々愛して死にたくなって こっちもフラフラやってんのん、オッケー？
Becoming reluctant to love and wanting to die, I'm wandering aimlessly too, okay?
Love, blah blah blah...
バーストからインスタントラヴァー
From burst to instant lover.
頭 体が馬鹿に絡まる ヘイ！
Head and body getting stupidly tangled. Hey!
ゴーストならアンデッドマナー
If you're a ghost, it's undead manners.
曖昧みだら 今は火花散らばそれがアンサー
Vague and lewd, now that the sparks are flying, that's the answer.
バーストからインスタントラヴァー
From burst to instant lover.
頭 体が馬鹿に絡まる ヘイ！
Head and body getting stupidly tangled. Hey!
ゴーストならアンデッドマナー
If you're a ghost, it's undead manners.
曖昧みだら 今は火花散らばそれがアンサー
Vague and lewd, now that the sparks are flying, that's the answer.
ワンモア
One more!
もー やっぱビッビラビったらいいじゃん POPな愛情 踊ったらいいじゃん
Geez, as I thought, it's fine to get jittery. It's fine to dance with POP affection.
みっともないから 嫉妬しまいな 発火しちゃうよ もう くっそだせえな
It's pathetic, so stow the jealousy. It's gonna ignite, man, you're so lame.
淋しくなったら 誰でもいいじゃん 産まればいいじゃん
If you get lonely, anyone will do. Why not just be born?
嫌々愛していきたくなって 死ぬまでピュアピュアやってんのん？
Becoming reluctant to love and live, you're gonna keep playing pure-pure until you die?
やっぱビッビラビったらいいじゃん BADなダンス ハマったらいいじゃん
As I thought, it's fine to get jittery. It's fine to get hooked on a BAD dance.
やっぱり好きとか やってられんわ 馬鹿じゃないの？ もう くっそだせえな
Saying you still like me and all that, I can't take it. Are you an idiot? Man, you're so lame.
淋しくなったら 誰でもいいじゃん 産まればいいじゃん
If you get lonely, anyone will do. Why not just be born?
嫌々愛して死にたくなって こっちもフラフラやってんのん？
Becoming reluctant to love and wanting to die, I'm wandering aimlessly too?
やっぱビッビラビったらいいじゃん とっくのとうに終わった想い
As I thought, it's fine to get jittery. Feelings that ended a long time ago.
みっともないとか 言ってごめんね 発火したいけど もうだめなんだ
Sorry for saying it's pathetic. I want to ignite, but I just can't anymore.
淋しくなったら 誰でもいいじゃん 産まればいいじゃん
If you get lonely, anyone will do. Why not just be born?
嫌々愛していきたくなって こっちもフラフラやってんのん、オッケー？
Becoming reluctant to love and live, I'm wandering aimlessly too, okay?
ヤヤヤヤ 悪い子さん
Ya-ya-ya-ya, bad child.
ママママ お相子じゃん
Ma-ma-ma-ma, we're even.
タタタタ 始めるよ
Ta-ta-ta-ta, let's start.
モット コノ穴 アイシテヨ
Love this hole more.
ヤヤヤヤ 悪い子さん
Ya-ya-ya-ya, bad child.
ママママ お相子じゃん
Ma-ma-ma-ma, we're even.
タタタタ 始めるよ
Ta-ta-ta-ta, let's start.
モット コノ穴 アイシテヨ
Love this hole more.
交わしたはずのない約束が
A promise we never made
今日も僕らの未来を奪おうとする
still tries to steal our future today.
欲しがっていたものを手にしても
Even when I get what I wanted,
素直に上手く笑えないのはなぜだろう
I wonder why I can't just smile naturally.
溢れる涙は弱さや後悔じゃない
These overflowing tears aren't from weakness or regret.
痛みが生んだカケラで
They're fragments born of pain.
どんな瞬間だって運命だってひとつだけ確かな
Whatever the moment or fate, there's only one thing
ものがあると知った
that I've learned is certain.
一りで考えちゃって今を迷うより
Rather than worrying alone and getting lost in the now,
明日を迎えに行くんだ
I'll go out to meet tomorrow.
ずっと持ってたい心の地雷スイッチは切ってない
I haven't turned off the heart's trigger I want to keep forever.
変わらない未来壊したい いつも僕を見てるありふれたメロディが
I want to break the unchanging future. This mundane melody is always watching me...
くだらないと人に笑われても
Even if people laugh and call it worthless,
キラキラなおさら輝くのはなぜだろう
I wonder why it sparkles even brighter.
何が本当で嘘か理屈じゃなくて
It's not about logic, what's true or false;
感じていたい心で
I want to feel it with my heart.
ずっと愛なんて幻想だって誤魔化したくないよ
I don't want to keep pretending that love is just an illusion,
傷ついたとしていい
even if it means getting hurt.
分かり合いたいと強く願うほど
Because the more I strongly wish to understand,
ぶつかることもあるから
the more we might clash.
泣けるくらい青空交差点で
At the intersection under the cry-inducing blue sky,
手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand.
10年後もこんなふうにいられるかな
I wonder if we can still be like this 10 years from now,
一緒に
together.
どんな瞬間だって運命だってひとつだけ確かな
Whatever the moment or fate, there's only one thing
ものがあると知った
that I've learned is certain.
限界だって困難だって諦めたくないよ
Even with limits or hardships, I don't want to give up,
このまま離さないで
so don't let go of me now.
固く握りしめた君の右手は
Your right hand, which I gripped tightly,
ぬくもりここにあるから
has a warmth that is right here.
はい！というわけで！
Yes! And with that!
4曲連続で聴いていただきました！
You've just heard four songs in a row!
どうだったでしょうか！？
How did you like it!?
わあああ！
Waaaa!
はい、結構ね、スバルのね、好きな曲とか
Yes, it was quite a section with Subaru's favorite songs
やりたいことをですね、こうギュッと詰め込んだパートになっています！
and things she wanted to do packed tightly together!
えー、ここからですね、いよいよ、ライブも終盤戦ということで！
Er, from here, the live is finally reaching its final stage!
えー、ここからはなんとちょっとみんなに告知があります！
Er, and from here, I actually have an announcement for everyone!
嬉しいお知らせです！
It's some happy news!
なんと！大空スバル6周年記念ライブのグッズ告知だ！
What! It's the goods announcement for Oozora Subaru's 6th Anniversary Live!
それではこちらをどうぞ！
Please take a look at this!
きたー！ということで今回も盛りだくさんのグッズ紹介いってみたいと思います！
It's here! So I'd like to introduce the abundance of goods this time as well!
今回のイラストは、しぐれうい母ちゃんに書いていただきました！
This time's illustration was drawn by Shigure Ui-kaachan!
母ちゃん、いつもありがとう！
Kaachan, thank you as always!
今回のグッズはマネージャー応援がコンセプトとなっています！
The concept for these goods is 'Supporting the Manager'!
さっそく見ていきましょう！まずは、こちら！
Let's take a look right away! First, this!
スバルがおうえん！！BIGアクリルスタンド！
'Subaru Supports You!!' BIG Acrylic Stand!
スバルがみんなを応援している
Subaru is supporting everyone...
スバルがおうえん!!BIGアクリルスタンド
Subaru is Cheering You On!! Big Acrylic Stand
しぐれうい先生描き下ろしイラストのビッグなアクリルスタンドです！
This is a big acrylic stand featuring an illustration by Shigure Ui-sensei!
スバルに応援されたい人にピッタリな存在感グッドな商品となっております！
This item has a great presence, perfect for those who want to be cheered on by Subaru!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
スバルがおうえん！ボイスキーホルダー！
Subaru is Cheering You On! Voice Keychain!
全6種類のボイスがランダムに再生されるボイスキーホルダーです！
This is a voice keychain that randomly plays a total of six types of voices!
応援ボイスなど盛りだくさんですので、ぜひみんな、いっぱい聞いてみてください！
It's packed with cheering voices and more, so please listen to them lots, everyone!
こちらのイラストは五真澪先生に書いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This illustration was drawn by Goma Rio-sensei! Thank you very much!
そして、続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
スバルのストップウォッチ風コインケース！
Subaru's Stopwatch-style Coin Case!
こちらはですね、通常衣装のストップウォッチをイメージしたコインケースになっております。
This is a coin case designed in the image of the stopwatch from my usual outfit.
普段使いしやすい商品ですので、ぜひみんなも使ってみてください！
It's an easy item for daily use, so please use it too, everyone!
さあ、まだまだありますよ！続いてはこちら！
Now, there's still more! Next up is this!
スバルのマネージャーノート！
Subaru's Manager Notebook!
こちらはですね、マネージャーモードのスバルが普段使っているマネージャーノートになっております。
This is the manager notebook that Manager-mode Subaru usually uses.
あと、普段はですね、RPGの実況なんかの時も使っています。ということで、
Also, I usually use it during things like RPG gameplay streams. So,
こちらも普段使いしやすいので、皆さんぜひチェックしてみてください！
this one is also easy to use daily, so please check it out, everyone!
そして、フルセット購入特典もあります！こちら、どうぞ！
And there's also a bonus for purchasing the full set! Here it is!
箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードとなっておりますので、
It's an instax-style bromide card with a foil-stamped replica signature,
ぜひこちらも要チェックですよ！
so be sure to check this out as well!
はい、ということで、改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！
Alright, so once again, here is the full set!
ぜひスバルにいっぱい応援されたいよー！という方は、チェックしてみてください！
If you want to be cheered on lots by Subaru, please check it out!
そして、さらにお知らせがあります！な、な、な、なんと！
And, there's even more news! Wh-wh-wh-what!
こちらをご覧ください！
Please take a look at this!
なんと！大空スバル 1st アルバム『Pleiades』が3月3日に発売となります！やったー！
Unbelievable! Oozora Subaru's 1st album 'Pleiades' will be released on March 3rd! Yay!
こちらのアルバムはですね、今まで出してきたスバルの思い出いっぱいの曲を一つのアルバムにギュギュギュギュっと詰め込みました！
This album is packed to the brim with all the songs full of Subaru's memories that I've released so far!
このあと披露する2曲の新曲や、いろんなホロメンに参加してもらった大空警察の曲まで！
From the two new songs I'll perform later to the Oozora Police song featuring various Hololive members!
10曲がですね、ギュッと詰まったアルバムになっております。ぜひいっぱい聴いてください！
It's an album packed with 10 songs. Please listen to it a lot!
特典もですね、6種類のランダムトレーディングカードや、メッセージカード、
Bonuses include six types of random trading cards, a message card,
そして、今回のですね、このライブのダイジェストMV視聴カードなど盛りだくさんですので、
and things like a digest MV viewing card for this live performance, so it's a lot,
ぜひ！ぜひ！ぜひ！買ってみてください！
so please! Please! Please! Try buying it!
よろしくお願いします！買って買って買ってー！
Thank you! Buy it, buy it, buy it!
ということで、以上、大空スバル6周年記念ライブのグッズ情報とアルバム情報でした！
So, that was the goods and album info for Oozora Subaru's 6th Anniversary Live!
みんな、いっぱい買ってくださーい！よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please buy lots! Thank you very much!
はい！そしてなんと、もういよいよライブも終盤戦ということで、
Yes! And unbelievable, the live performance is finally reaching its final stages,
それでは、次の曲の準備をして、
so now, I'll get ready for the next song,
よいしょ。はい。
heave-ho. Alright.
それでは、聴いてください。
Well then, please listen.
青のすみか。
Ao no Sumika (Where Our Blue Is).
青のすみか / 作詞・作曲: キタニタツヤ
Ao no Sumika / Lyrics & Composition: Tatsuya Kitani
どこまでも 続くような 青の季節は
The blue season that seems to go on forever,
四つ並ぶ 瞳の前を 遮るものは 何も無い
There is nothing blocking the way in front of the four eyes lined up.
アスファルト 蝉時雨を 反射して
Reflecting the asphalt and the chorus of cicadas,
君という 沈黙が 聞こえなくなる
the silence that is you becomes inaudible.
この日々が 色褪せる 僕と違う 君の匂いを知ってしまっても
Even if these days fade and I learn your scent, which is different from mine,
置き忘れてきた 永遠の そこに
there at the eternity left behind,
今でも 青が澄んでいる
the blue is still clear even now.
今でも 青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue is clear.
どんな祈りも 言葉も 近づけるのに 届かなかった
No matter the prayer or words, I could get close but they didn't reach.
まるで静かな 恋のような 頬を伝った 夏のような 色の中
Like a quiet love, like the summer that trickled down my cheek, in those colors,
君を呪う 言葉が ずっと喉の奥に つっかえてる
the words cursing you have been stuck in the back of my throat.
「また会えるよね」って
'We'll meet again, right?'
声にならない 声
The voice that won't become a voice.
昼下がり じめつく風の 季節は
The season of the humid breeze in the early afternoon,
思い馳せる まだ何ものでも無かった 僕らの肖像
makes me think of our portraits from when we were still nothing.
何もかも 分かち合えた 筈だった
We were supposed to be able to share everything.
あの日から 少しずつ 君と違う 僕という 呪いが 太っていく
From that day, bit by bit, the curse that is me, different from you, grows.
君の笑顔の奥の 憂いを
The sorrow behind your smile,
見落とした事 悔や
I regret missing...
...見つけ出して
...find me.
La la la...
あだ花と咲き　散っていく
Blooming as sterile flowers, then scattering.
君にさよなら
Goodbye to you.
今でも青が澄んでいる
Even now, the blue is clear.
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue remains clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayer or the words,
近づけるのには届かなかった
they weren't enough to reach and bring us closer.
まるで静かな恋のような
Like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような
like a summer that trickled down my cheek.
色の中君を贈る言葉が
Amidst the colors, the words to send you off
ずっと喉の奥に仕えている
have been stuck in the back of my throat all this time.
「また会えるよね」って
Saying "We'll meet again, right?"
声にならない声
A voice that couldn't become sound.
無限に膨張する銀河の粒
Like the particles of a galaxy expanding infinitely,
ように夢の隙間をこぼれた
they spilled through the gaps of a dream.
Starlight　繋いで
Starlight, connecting us,
繰り返してく衝動
a repeating impulse.
僕らは止まらない
We won't stop.
きらり輝いてゆけ
Shine brightly and go forth.
星灯
Starlight
作詞・作曲・編曲：DIVELA
Lyrics, Composition, & Arrangement: DIVELA
地を蹴った足取りは
My footsteps kicking off the ground
弾んだリズムで
with a bouncing rhythm,
君の心の鍵をまた鳴らす
strike the key to your heart once more.
光は線となって
The light becomes a line
やがて形作った
and eventually forms
キャンバスの上灯る道
a path lit up on the canvas.
満開　星明かり
Starlight in full bloom,
迷いはない　また前を向けるから
there's no hesitation, because I can look forward again.
Fly again　飛ぶんだ
Fly again, I'm taking flight.
導かれたこの舞台
This stage I was guided to,
いつか聞こえる日まで
until the day it's finally heard.
空高く掲げた
Raised high toward the sky,
みんなの手を重ね
we overlap our hands,
ぶち壊した限界のその先へ
going beyond the limits we've shattered.
思わず涙が
When tears seem
溢れ落ちそうな
about to overflow,
そんな夜には連れて行くよさぁ一緒に
I'll take you away on a night like that—come on, together!
夜空に差し込む
Shining into the night sky,
煌めくスターレイル
a sparkling Star Rail.
いつでも届けたい
I always want to deliver it,
笑顔になる歌があるから
because there's a song that makes you smile.
Be the star　歌おう
Be the star, let's sing.
一面染まる金世界
A golden world painting everything.
今もまだ焼き付いて
Even now, it's still burned into me.
空高く響いた
Echoing high in the sky,
激情また最高潮
the passion is at its peak again.
昨日よりも駆けるんだ遠くまで
I'll run further than I did yesterday.
Fly again　飛ぶんだ
Fly again, I'm taking flight.
指先触れた結晶
A crystal my fingertips touched.
Be the star　なるんだ
Be the star, I'll become
君の一等星
your brightest star.
Starlight　輝け
Starlight, shine on.
僕らはいつだってここにいるよ
We'll always be right here.
願いよ届け
May my wish reach you.
無限の宇宙を
Through the infinite universe,
流れる星となって
becoming a shooting star,
キミと僕ら照らすその先へ
illuminating you and us, toward what lies ahead.
超えて　超えて
Surpassing it, going beyond.
どこまでも 僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
No matter how far, we'll keep running through it all
傷ついて傷ついたって 明日は笑っていたいな
Even if we get hurt, I want to be laughing tomorrow
間違いも いつかのための正解でしょ？
Even mistakes are the right answers for some future time, right?
転んだって泣いたって 不器用でいいじゃん さあいくんだ
Even if we fall or cry, it's okay to be clumsy. Come on, let's go!
星灯 - 113の空へ -
作詞：TKT from AliA / 作曲・編曲：EREN from AliA
Hoshiairi - To the 113th Sky -
Lyrics: TKT from AliA / Composition & Arrangement: EREN from AliA
色褪せたこの世界で 繰り返していくだけの毎日
In this faded world, every day is just a repeat of the last
言えずにいた言葉を 風に乗せてひとり呟いた
I whispered the words I couldn't say into the wind, all alone
素直になるためには まだまだ勇気が足りないけど
I still don't have enough courage to be honest
水しぶきあげて飛び込んだ 目を瞑りながら
But I dove in, making a splash, with my eyes closed
悪天候に虹を描いて 青く塗りつぶした
Drawing a rainbow in bad weather, painting it all blue
扉開けて飛び出そうよ はじめましての未来へ
Let's open the door and jump out to a future we've never seen before
どこまでも 僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
No matter how far, we'll keep running through it all
傷ついて傷ついたって 明日は笑っていたいな
Even if we get hurt, I want to be laughing tomorrow
間違いも いつかのための正解でしょ？
Even mistakes are the right answers for some future time, right?
顔上げて走り出そう ひとりぼっちがふたりで
Look up and start running, two lonely souls together
転んだって泣いたって 不器用でいいじゃん さあいくんだ
Even if we fall or cry, it's okay to be clumsy. Come on, let's go!
何が正解で不正解かも ときどきわからなくなって
Sometimes I lose track of what's right and what's wrong
涙堪えながら 答えを探し続けていたんだ
Holding back my tears, I kept searching for the answer
溢れた涙 見つけた笑顔 全部宝箱にしまって
The tears that spilled, the smiles I found, I'll put them all in a treasure chest
いつか立ち止まったら 思い出してまた笑いたいな
If I ever come to a stop, I want to remember them and laugh again
満天の星空を描いて 願い事をしよう
Let's draw a sky full of stars and make a wish
流れ星も描き足そうか 僕次第で変われるんだ
Shall we add some shooting stars? I can change, it's up to me
いつまでもこの日々が続くといいな
I hope these days will last forever
望んだって叶わない ことだらけでも悪くないな
Even if most wishes don't come true, it's not so bad
明日へとこの歌が届くといいな
I hope this song reaches into tomorrow
手を取って笑い合って ありのままを描いていくんだ
Holding hands and laughing together, we'll draw it just as it is
どこまでも 僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
No matter how far, we'll keep running through it all
傷ついて傷ついたって 明日は笑っていたいな
Even if we get hurt, I want to be laughing tomorrow
間違いも いつかのための正解だから
Because even mistakes are the right answers for some future time
顔上げて走り出そう ひとりぼっちがふたりで
Look up and start running, two lonely souls together
転んだって泣いたって 不器用でいいじゃん さあいくんだ
Even if we fall or cry, it's okay to be clumsy. Come on, let's go!
どこまでも...
No matter how far...
駆け抜けていくんだ...
...we'll keep running through it all
★映像協力★
スタジオ スープ
★Video Cooperation★
Studio Soup
君とスバルの未来が幸せで
いっぱいでありますように！！
May your future with me
be full of happiness!!